

ABOUT ME

Accomplished and ambitious event and project manager with 10 years' experience in event and project planning. Strongly focused and result-orientated with the ability to complete tasks accurately in a fast-paced environment while meeting deadlines. Innovative and dedicated team player with experience in team leadership.

WEBSITES & SOCIAL LINKS

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulelkington-a6925683/

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth 25 November 1986

NationalitySouth African

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

AFRIKAANS

PAUL ELKINGTON

PROJECT MANAGER - LOGISTICS ABSA CAPE EPIC

23 Trinity Street, Cape Town, 7441, South Africa

+2782 831 8448

pje@live.co.za

WORK EXPERIENCE

CAPE EPIC (PTY) LTD

Cape Town
Sep 2018 - Present

Project Manager - Logistics Absa Cape Epic

- Management of crew
- Budget planning and management
- Strategic planning
- Contractor engagement and contract negotiation
- Venue identification and engagements
- Venue maps and layouts
- Logistics requirements
- Event Master Schedule
- Successful delivery of logistic elements on event
- Management across multiple events including:
- World's premier MTB stage race (Absa Cape Epic)
- South Africa's favourite 3 day MTB stage race (Wines 2 Whales)
- South African UCI XCO MTB World Cup in South Africa

CAPE EPIC (PTY) LTD

Cape Town
Jan 2017 - Present

Event manager - UCI MTB World Cup Stellenbosch

- Budget planning and management
- Strategic planning
- Management of crew
- Management of logistics team
- Sponsor engagements
- Management of suppliers
- Venue identification and engagements
- Venue design and layouts
- Venue management
- Scheduling

CAPE EPIC (PTY) LTD

Cape Town
Oct 2016 - Present

Project Coordinator - Logistics Absa Cape Epic

- Budget planning and management
- Venue maps and layouts
- Contractor engagement and contract negotiation
- Logistic requirements
- Successful delivery of logistic elements on event

DIRTOPIA

Stellenbosch Jul 2016 - Sep 2016

Event Manager

- Designing and managing event plans and layouts
- Liaising with and managing service providers
- Managing all logistics and AV
- Managing budgets to achieve targets
- Obtain relevant permits and source venues
- Managing all aspects of buildup and strike of events
- Sourcing and managing event staff
- Managing event on the day/days of the event.

SKILLS

TIME MANAGEMENT

MULTI-TASK MANAGEMENT

COMPUTER PROFICIENT

RESULTS-ORIENTED

TEAM MANAGEMENT

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

DOMESTIC AND INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

CUSTOMER SERVICE

TEAM PLAYER

EVENT SEQUENCING

PROBLEM SOLVING

HOBBIES

SURFING, RUNNING, CAMPING, MUSIC AND SPORTS ENTHUSIAST

DRIVING LICENSE

Driving license category Code 8

FIERA MILANO

Cape Town, Durban & JHB Sep 2014 - Jul 2016

Operations and Event Coordinator

- Designing and managing floor plans
- Managing event projects
- Liaising with and managing service providers and stakeholders
- Developing and managing event itineraries
- Managing budgets to achieve targets
- Obtain relevant permits and source venues
- Managing all logistics and AV
- Managing all aspects of buildup and strike of events
- Liaising with clients
- Sourcing and managing event staff
- Managing event on days of the event

ADVENTURE WORKS

Hout Bay, Cape Town Jul 2014 - Sep 2014

Operations Manager

- Managing event projects
- Developing and managing itineraries
- Adhere to budgets to achieve required targets
- Arrange all necessary bookings
- Obtain relevant permits and source venues
- Managing logistics
- Liaising with clients on requirements
- Sourcing and managing event staff
- Managing all branding
- Organising and facilitating a variety of events ranging from adventure activities to corporate events

MAKWEDS

Cape Town
Jan 2012 - Jun 2013

Events Coordinator

Hosting successful S.A International rugby events and a variety of club sports events. Managing all brand activations

VERDIS SOCIAL LOUNGE

Cape Town Aug 2010 - Jul 2013

Manager

- Organize and manage VIP events from catering to design
- Ensuring customer satisfaction is maintained at all times
- Managing all brand activations
- Maintaining stock and circulation of stock items
- Conducting cash ups
- Managing staff and managing stock

JUMEIRAH DUBAI - WILD WADI WATER PARK

Dubai Jul 2008 - Dec 2009

Team Leader of Operations

- Working with and managing over 40 different nationalities, ensuring a high standard of customer service is always maintained
- Manage both minor and critical situations with guests who are in distress
- Manage VIP clients and functions
- Conduct performance appraisals of associates in department
- Cross trained with Jumeirah Hotels in events industry

EDUCATION

REFERENCES

GLYN BROOMBERG Cape Epic (PTY) LTD

T: +2772 170 7547 **E:** glynbberg@gmail.com

JASON RADE Fiera Milano

T: +2772 099 1785 **E:** jasonrade@yahoo.com

AUDREY LLEWELLYN Verdis Social Lounge T: +2772 783 6714

NATASHA KROS Makweds

T: +2778 363 2440

MORANA SIMAC Wild Wadi Water Park - Dubai

T: Skype - morriesmac77

CAPE PENINSULA UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

Cape Town 2012

Higher National Diploma

Subjects Covered:

- Communications
- Information Technology
- Tourism Guidance
- Business Finance
- Project Management
- Marketing
- Events Theory
- Event Practical